fordparts.com 2015-09-05

# Privacy Policy | FordParts.com

## General Statement:

> > We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. This privacy statement explains our policies and practices regarding on-line customer information. It is through this disclosure that we intend to provide you with a level of comfort and confidence in how we collect, use, and safeguard personal and other information we collect or that you provide through this website, and how you can contact us if you have any questions or concerns. It is our sincere hope that by explaining our data handling practices we will develop a trusting and long-lasting relationship with you.

## Information About Our Organization and Website and General Data Collection Practices:

> > This Privacy Statement applies to FordParts.com. FordParts.com is owned and maintained by Ford Customer Service Division, 16800 Executive Plaza Drive, Dearborn, MI, 48126.
>> 
>> The business purpose of this website is to facilitate sales of Ford Motor Company Genuine Parts and Motorcraft® Parts from Ford Motor Company Dealers to customers.
>> 
>> When you visit this site analytics providers may collect information about your online activity over time and across websites. 
>> 
>> Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret web browser-based “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) signals other than cookies, Ford Motor Company does not currently respond to undefined “DNT” signals to its US websites. 
>> 
>> Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies; however, this may prevent you from having access to some functions or services on our sites.

## Personally Identifiable Information We Collect From You:

> > When you visit FordParts.com we will not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. For purposes of this Privacy Statement “personally identifiable information” is information that identifies you as an individual, for example your name, street address, telephone number, and e-mail address (and credit card number if you place an order). If you opt not to provide us with personally identifiable information you can still access our website, however you may be unable to participate in certain promotions or receive product information or have a purchase order fulfilled. 
>> 
>> Our primary goal in collecting personally identifiable information from you when you visit FordParts.com is to provide you the functionality and services that you need to have a meaningful and customized experience while using the site features. We need to collect personally identifiable information in order to verify user identity, pre-populate fields for user convenience, fulfill purchase orders, and conduct surveys and targeted marketing campaigns, including honoring your request to receive text messages or mobile alerts regarding special money-saving service coupons and promotional offers.
>> 
>>   This site may use a third party to deliver site functionality. An explanation on data collection methods and how they work is included in Methods Used to Collect Information.

## How We Use the Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:

> > _Personally identifiable information collected on FordParts.com may be used to:_
>> 
>>   * Fulfill a site user request (lead generation, questions about products/dealer pricing, send marketing or promotional materials, including but not limited to, those sent through e-mail or through cell phone such as text message as requested by you, or other information)
>>   * Fulfill and deliver an order for goods or services such as Motorcraft® or Ford Motor Company Genuine Parts.
>>   * Respond to your comments or requests for information
>>   * Meet a request for or to develop new products or services
>>   * Make the user experience more customer friendly
>>   * Contact you if necessary in the course of processing or shipping an order for products or services
>>   * Generate site analytics that improve our site layout, content, product offerings and services
>>   * Compile user data that is stored in our corporate database and may be used for marketing and other purposes
>>   * Match personal data collected here with data about you that we collect offline
>>   * Comply with legal requirements
>> 

## Other (Non-Personally Identifiable) Information We Collect From Site Visitors:

> Customers may provide shopping experience comments and ratings in connection with a transaction. Your dealer will be able to view comments and any specific rating you provide. Your comments will not be publicly displayed on the FordParts.com website. Dealers and Ford will not be able to alter the ratings or comments in any way. Only your dealership, Ford Motor Company, and any vendors engaged to perform rating tool services will be able to view specific ratings and comments. 
> 
> FordParts.com collects other “non-personally identifiable” information from site visitors. This means that we do not track these items on an individual basis that identifies the site visitor, but rather gather and collect this information on an aggregate [or anonymous] basis that includes all site visitors. Non-personally identifiable information includes tracking the site pages that are visited or the amount of time spent on our site. 
> 
> Our primary goal in collecting non-personally identifiable information from you is to be able to perform site metrics that allow us to improve the functionality of the website.
> 
> We may use session and persistent "cookies," spot light ads/web beacons/banner ads or links, or third-party click tracking analytics tools such as Adobe and Google Analytics to collect aggregate or other non-personally identifiable information about site visitors. An explanation on collection methods and how they work is included in Methods Used to Collect Information.

## How We Use the Aggregate or Non-Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:

> Non-Personally identifiable information collected on FordParts.com may be used:
> 
>   * Compile aggregate and statistical data to help in website design and to identify popular features
>   * Measure site activity to allow us to update our site to better meet user wants and needs
> FordParts.com utilizes non-personally identifiable information data for the purpose of performing analytics on the users' experience while visiting this site. This analysis: 
>     * Is performed on an aggregate level and does not identify you or your information personally
>     * Involves the use of a third-party vendor acting on behalf of FordParts.com
>     * Is performed in order to improve our website and the user experience
>     * May include the use of session and/or persistent cookies to track user movement across this and other Ford Motor Company websites or to track other events within or across this and other Ford Motor Company websites
>     * Any information that is provided to the third-party vendor is to be used only for the purpose of performing the analytics and compiling reports of the data. The third-party vendor is restricted from using this data in any other way other than to provide these services to Ford Motor Company and Ford authorized dealers and they may not share or resell this data
> 

## Methods to Collect Information:

A “cookie” is a small text file that helps us in many ways to make your visit to our website more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, cookies avoid you having to log in every time you come back to one of our websites. They also allow us to tailor a website or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences.  There are a couple different types of cookies.

"session" cookie is stored only in your computer's working memory (RAM) and only lasts for your browsing session. When you close all your browser's windows, or when you shut down your computer, the session cookie disappears forever. 

"persistent" cookie is stored on your computer's hard drive until a specified date, which could be tomorrow, next week, or 10 years from now. Persistent cookies stay on your computer until either a) they expire,) they are overwritten with newer cookies, c) you manually remove them. Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies, however, this may prevent you from having access to some site functions or features. 

This site may use a third party to deliver site functionality such as fulfilling your request to purchase items from our online store, calculation of sales tax credit card processing and site functionality. In performing this function the third party may place a persistent cookie on your computer or have to gather personally identifiable information from you in order to facilitate the processing of your purchase. 

This site may use a third-party click tracking analytics tools such as Adobe and Google Analytics to capture click through statistics. 

FordParts.com may use spot light ads and web beacons which are site instrumentation tools that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or not and, if so, how many times. When you ask us to send you information on a promotion or a newsletter, we may use web beacons to establish how many of the emails are actually opened. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon. 

Users may be directed to FordParts.com via banner ads or site links. Ads or site links that are placed by FordParts.com use cookies or web beacons to deliver metrics on the effectiveness of the ads or links. They do not collect personally identifiable information from the user. 

Third-party advertising networks that serve ads onto FordParts.com may use cookies and/or web beacons in their advertisements. FordParts.com retains no control over such third party cookies and/or web beacons and does not have access to the information related to third party cookies and/or web beacons. 

Online Advertising: Ford may contract with vendors to place advertisements on non-Ford websites. When you visit a non-Ford website, these vendors may target Ford advertisements to you based on information about your previous online activity that the vendor has collected using web tracking tools (e.g., cookies and web beacons). Additionally, Ford advertisements may contain web tracking tools such as cookies and web beacons to collect information on the effectiveness of the advertisements and to deliver future targeted advertisements and other messages to you. These web tracking tools collect information such as IP address, the page visited, and time of day. 

## Sharing Your Information:

> FordParts.com does not share, sell, or rent personally identifiable information with independent companies for their own use without providing you a choice.
> 
> Personally identifiable information that you provide to us in the course of requesting a product or service through this website may be gathered and stored in one or more of our corporate databases and be used for purposes of contacting you for things like promotional offers, marketing programs, or other communications from this website or other Ford Motor Company websites. 
> 
> We may share personally identifiable information that we collect about you with other companies within the Ford Motor Company family of companies or subsidiaries. Our "family of companies" is the group of companies related to us by common control or ownership. We share information within this "family" as a normal part of conducting business and offering products and services to our customers.
> 
> Personally identifiable information that you provide to FordParts.com may be shared with our authorized Ford and Lincoln Mercury dealers. This is necessary in order to answer product questions, request a price quote and fulfill a parts order. The dealer is not restricted by FordParts.com in their use of your data.
> 
> Vendors, contractors or partners of FordParts.com who have access to your personally identifiable information in connection with providing services for FordParts.com are required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing FordParts.com.
> 
> Site metrics for FordParts.com may be shared with other Ford Motor Company websites, subsidiaries, affiliates, or Ford authorized dealers. The information shared will be aggregate data and will not include any of your personally identifiable information.
> 
> FordParts.com will disclose your personally identifiable information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Ford Motor Company or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Ford Motor Company and this site; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Ford Motor Company, its web sites, or the public.

## Access To and Control Over the Use of Your Personally Identifiable Information:

> To correct or update your personally identifiable information use the My Profile function. You will be asked for your ID and password so that we may be able to process your changes. FordParts.com will use reasonable efforts to correct any factual inaccuracies in your information.
> 
> The scope of access available for this request is for information stored in the database that holds the data for FordParts.com. Any personally identifiable information that has been collected from you on other Company websites will not be accessible or changeable through the processing of this request.

## Security of Your Information:

> Safeguarding information of visitors to our website is important to us. We use systems, policies and procedures to maintain accuracy of information and to protect information from loss, misuse or alteration.
> 
> When you send personally identifiable information, such as credit card numbers or telephone numbers, to FordParts.com we use "Secure Socket Layers" or SSL to protect your data. SSL is encryption technology that helps safeguard your personally identifiable information against misuse by unauthorized individuals.
> 
> Vendors, contractors or partners of FordParts.com who have access to your personally identifiable information in connection with providing services for FordParts.com are required to keep the information confidential.
> 
> Vendors are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for FordParts.com.

## Consent to Processing:

> By visiting this site and by providing your personally identifiable information to us, you understand and consent to the collection, use, processing, transfer, and disclosure of your personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information globally --- including to the United States -- in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Therefore, by visiting this site and by providing such information, you consent to the transfer of such information across country borders, and to the use, processing, and disclosure of such information in global locations as required. Your consent shall be deemed to include your consent to transfer of the personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable information to locations that may have different levels of privacy protection than in your own country.

## Links to Other Sites:

> FordParts.com provides links to other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of all sites which you visit, including those whose links are provided so that you can understand how those sites collect, use and share your information. FordParts.com is not responsible for the privacy statements, content or data handling practices on other websites.
> 
> FordParts.com also provides dealer and vehicle locator services which are provided by a third-party vendor.  In order to provide you with the closest dealers, we may need to collect your IP address to determine your general location, or we may ask you to provide location information such as zip code or City and State.  In instances where we use a third-party vendor to provide dealer locator services, we will provide them a zip code.  We encourage you to review the terms of service and the privacy policies of these mapping service providers.  For pages that use Bing, you agree to be bound by the Microsoft Service Agreement and Microsoft Online Privacy Statement. 
> 
>    If you choose to utilize the ShareThis widget to share content on this website with your friends, please note that ShareThis is an independent third party and is not a vendor, contractor or partner of FordParts.com.  All information (personally identifiable or aggregate) that is collected by the ShareThis widget is collected by ShareThis and is subject to the ShareThis Privacy Policy and not the FordParts.com Privacy Statement.  

## Children’s Privacy:

> FordParts.com does not knowingly intend to collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age.
> 
> If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information a parent or guardian of that child may contact us at [support@oeconnection.com](mailto:support@oeconnection.com) if they want this information deleted from our records. We will then make reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from the database that stores information for FordParts.com.

## Contacting Us:

> If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this online privacy statement for FordParts.com, FordParts.com privacy practices, or have any questions regarding the contents of this website please contact us at [support@oeconnection.com](mailto:support@oeconnection.com).
> 
> FordParts.com is committed to working with consumers to obtain a fair and rapid resolution of any complaints or disputes about privacy and the handling of your data. FordParts.com will be happy to respond to your questions and comments.

## Privacy Statement Effective Date and Revision Days:

> Occasionally we may update the privacy statement for FordParts.com in order to reflect any changes to the website or our privacy practices. If we update this statement, the new statement will be posted to the website ten (10) days prior to the changes taking effect.
> 
> The effective date of this privacy statement is December 20, 2013.
